Current Address:

Exeter Ave, McKinney, TX 75070

Daniel Lu

(479) 747-5683 Daniel1992930@gmail.com Permanent Address: Exeter Ave, McKinney, TX 75070

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas

Master of Engineering, Degree in Electrical Engineering

Arkanasa Tech University, College Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering, Degree in Electrical Engineering

August 2016 – May 2018

August 2012 – May 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks: PLSQL/T-SQL, Java, R, Python, C#, Spark, SpringBoot, PowerShell, DAX

Operating Systems: Windows Server 2008R2/2012/2016, Linux Database: Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014/2016, Oracle 12c

Tools: SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), SSRS, SSIS, SSAS, Informatica, Power BI, Tableau, Hadoop, Docker, Git

SUMMARY

One Data developer who has about 3 years of focused experiences in Data Analysis/Data Engineer/BI development area in fields like financial, health care and information security. Experiences in SQL Server database analysis, modeling, development, implementation, trouble shooting and quality management.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Ohio Department of Aging

June 2020 - Present

Data Analysis, Tableau/SQL/ETL Developer

- Building queries, functions, and stored procedures to generate data with significant translation required in some cases
- Working with various sources of data coming to a centralized SQL Server data warehouse
- · Modifying, debugging and tuning the existing old Stored Procedures to meet the new requirements
- Design Tableau/Power BI data visualization utilizing cross tabs, maps, scatter plots, pies and bar charts
- · Automating environment build and provisioning using virtualization, containerization and orchestration tools with Docker, VM Ware
- Developed SSRS reports. Optimized SQL queries for processing huge result sets by rewriting the queries, implementing table-valued functions or stored procedures
- Designed and enhanced the ETL packages and processes, implemented data transformation rules and data validations into the enterprise data warehouses (EDW)
- Develop MS SQL Business Intelligence (BI) reports and applications and other reports and applications using T-SQL, C#, and other designated tools
- Wrote Batch and PowerShell scripts to run jobs through windows task scheduler.

Baker HughesSQL Server/ ETL Developer

August 2019 – April 2020

- Worked as a primary SQL developer in creating complex Stored Procedures, triggers, cursors, tables, views and other SQL joins and statements for applications
- · Used SQL Server Profiler and Extended Events to trace long running queries for optimizing databases
- · Wrote scripts in Python for Extracting Data from JSON and XML files and schedule in Airflow
- · Worked with Docker images, Docker hub and Docker registries
- Performed code reviews, analyzed execution plans, and re-factor inefficient code Follows data standards, resolved data issues, completed unit testing and completed system documentation for ETL processes
- Experience with data cleansing and Data migration for accurate reporting. Thoroughly analyze the data and integrated different data sources to process matching functions.
- Develop an application use C# for data analysis team in order to pull the specific data they need.
- · Worked on Hadoop, python, Spark to build ETL and Data Processing systems having various data sources and data targets

CIT Bank

May 2018 - June 2019

- SQL Server /Tableau/Data model/ETL Developer, Production Support
- Built an automated data visualization platform for Treasury team to manage and analyze financial data
 Provides and supports the implementation of business solutions (e.g. develops data models, data movement processes, report
- development, etc.)
 Collaborate with analysts and department leaders to design, build and customize reports and reporting packages using SQL Server, SSIS, SSRS, Tableau.
- Troubleshoots BI-related problems, fixes bugs and tunes for performance
- Transferred data from various data sources/business systems including MS Excel, MS Access, Flat Files, Oracle etc. to SQL Server using SSIS various features such as multitasking, conditional split, union, union all, merge, lookup, fuzzy lookup, etc
- · Providing support in designing, developing, analyzing, testing, debugging, and executing C# programs for windows desktop.
- Performed code reviews, analyzed execution plans, and re-factor inefficient code Follows data standards, resolved data issues, completed unit testing and completed system documentation for ETL processes
- Used DataStage as an ETL tool to extract data from sources systems, loaded the data into the ORACLE database.